我叫梅林达·戈登
My name is Melinda Gordon.
我结了婚  住在一个小镇上
I'm married, I live in a small town,
经营一家古董店
And I own an antique shop.
我也许和你相似
I might be just like you.
但当我还是小姑娘时
Except that from the time I was a little girl,
我就能同亡者交流
I knew that I could talk to the dead.
没事的  亲爱的
It's all right, honey.
祖母称他们为地缚灵
Earthbound spirits,my grandmother called them.
他们在人间滞留  因为他们有未了的心愿
They're stuck here because they have unfinished business with the living
他们找我寻求帮助
And they come to me for help.
讲述我的故事  就是讲述他们的故事
In order to tell you my story, I have to tell you theirs.
Three Days Grace - Pain
* Pain, without love *
* Pain, can't get enough.  Pain, I like it rough *
* Cause I'd rather feel pain than nothing at all *
* Pain, without love.  Pain, I can't get enough *
* Pain, I like it rough *
* Cause I'd rather feel pain than nothing at all *
* rather feel pain than nothing at all *
* rather feel pain *
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
我们是3天宽限乐队
We are Three Days Grace.
马上回来
We'll be right back.
你说带我出来跳舞
When you said that we were going out dancing,
我没想到指的是这个
I didn't think this was what you meant.
我说的是可能会有跳舞
I--I said there might be dancing.
你的原话是
Your exact words were,
我等不及把你领入舞池了
"I cannot wait to get you out on the dance floor."
行了  蹦上蹦下也是跳舞啊
Come on. Jumping up and down can be dancing.
还需要酒吗
Another round, folks?
行  两杯就好了
Yeah, yeah.  2 would be great.
布兰登  乐队叫你
Brandon!  Order up for the band.
抱歉  稍等片刻
Sorry, guys. Give me one sec.
你看这人眼熟吗
Does that guy look familiar to you?
不熟
I don't think so.
-你呢  -说不清
- You?  - I don't know.
-酒来了 -布兰登  你不来一段吗
- Here you go, guys.  - Hey, Brandon. Aren't you playing?
唱得好
Good Job.
别扫兴
Don't let us down.
-行了  来段吧  -不不不
- Come on, you gotta play.  - No, no, no.
大家在为你欢呼  来段吧
Look the people hail for you. You gotta play.
给你把吉他
Here, I got a guitar right here.
尽请欣赏
Hear it up, man.
太厉害了
He's amazing.
等等
Oh, wait a minute.
我就说看着眼熟
That's why I know this guy.
他以前是深红鸽子乐队的
He used to play for Crimson Doves.
-谁  -深红鸽子  本地的乐队
- Who?  - Crimson doves. They were a local band,
很受欢迎
Big favorite.
前几年  他们出过张很棒的专辑
They released this great album a few years back,
随后就突然消失了
and then they just kinda disappeared.
你感觉到了吗
Do you feel that?
十
Ten.
怎么了
What? What's going on?
让我猜猜
Let me guess.
吉米·亨德里克斯的鬼魂作祟[电吉他大师]
That wasn't the ghost of Jimi Hendrix?
对怯场有新的解释了
But it gave new meaning to stage fright.
鬼语者  第二季  第9集
九的诅咒
这么有才的人  怎么会在这工作
You know, why does a guy like that work here?
他应该上滚石封面
I mean, he should be on the cover of Rolling Stone,
而不是当酒保
not serving drinks.
也许这儿的小费超多
Maybe he gets monster tips here.
也许有鬼魂不想让他自己喜欢的事
Or maybe a ghost is trying to stop him from doing what he loves.
我讨厌那样
I hate that.
人死了  无法释然  这可以理解
You're dead, you can't move on, I get it.
但别去惹活人
But don't mess with the living,
尤其是像他这样有天赋的人
especially when they're as talented as he is.
我去把车开来
I'm gonna get the jeep.
在这等我  小心着凉
You stay here, you stay warm.
到家后  再解决鬼的事吧
We'll get this ghost into therapy when we get home.
好吧
All right.
你好  你在台上很棒
Oh, hi! Hey, you were great up there.
谢谢
Oh, thanks.
我没有把酒送过来  是吗
Aw, I never did get you those drinks, did I?
我们也不想喝了
We cut ourselves off.
我叫梅林达
I'm Melinda.
很高兴见到你
Nice to meet you.
刚发生的事很奇怪  你还好吗
It was weird what happened. Were you ok?
没事  只是反馈的问题
Yeah, it's just some feedback problems.
以前也发生过
It's happened before.
真的吗  以前在深红鸽子时也这样吗
Oh, really? Like when you used to play with, uh, Crimson Doves?
你是歌迷吗
Are you a fan?
我丈夫是
My husband was.
他告诉你诅咒的事了吗
So he told you about the curse?
没有  什么诅咒
No. What curse?
无聊的市井传说而已
Just a bad urban legend.
睡个好觉
Have a good night.
你有时间能聊聊吗
Well, do you have a second to talk?
行了吧  你真觉得这东西能卖三千块
Come on. You really think you can get $3,000 for this?
当然了  据传这是大门乐队用过的
Easy. It's rumored that The Doors played on it.
大门乐队是啥
What are The Doors?
这东西怎么卖得掉
But how are you gonna sell it?
都坏了  还得加几个新踏板
It's broken. It needs a new one of...those pedals.
我认识个翻新商
Well, I worked with a refurbisher,
他名片还在我这儿
and his card's still on file.
他还想买套公寓  如果有卖主的话
He's also looking to buy a condo if someone wants to sell him one.
-我的宝啊  梅林达  -谢谢
- Serendipity, the name is Melinda.  - Thank you.
我先去看看我的日程
I will have to check my schedule,
应该是有空的  对吧
but I think we're free, right?
我还有一大堆作业要喂狗呢
I have a ton of homework that the dog needs to eat.
好吧
Ok, fine.
你到家后我要检查作业
But I want to see it when you get home.
好吧
Ok.
再见  内德
Bye, Ned.
过去一周真可谓”乐趣“多多啊
Yeah. That's a lot of fun to live with for the past week.
怎么回事
What's going on?
查理的生日快到了
Charlie's birthday is coming up.
我知道  怪怪的
I know. Weird.
他已经死了
He's dead.
但
But...
给他庆生是一个习惯
celebrating his birthday is just a little way
好让我们感受到他与我们同在
for us to keep his spirit with us.
合情合理
Actually, it makes perfect sense.
是啊
Yeah, well...
内德不怎么喜欢
Ned's not so crazy about it.
他知道那天快到了
He knows it's coming up,
于是就想方设法回避这事
and he's doing everything he can to avoid it,
同时也就  回避了我
and by extension, avoid me.
瞧  我找到了
Hey, look. I found it.
我要去找新键踏板了
So I'm gonna be on the hunt for a new pedal.
-你好  -你好  帅哥
- Howdy.  - Hello, handsome.
你好  迪莉娅
Hi, Delia.
今天吉姆从工作中学到
Listen Jim learned at work today:
不要被抓到在上班时间上网
Don't get caught surfing myspace at work.
你在嘲笑我吗
Ooh, is there mocking?
你要向13岁的小女孩靠齐了吗
Something along the lines of you being a 13-year-old girl?
很搞笑
Very funny.
这都是值得的
It was all worth it because...
深红鸽子的网站
a link for the Crimson Doves.
"安息吧  贾里德"
"Rest in peace, Jared".
他是主唱
Yeah. He's the lead singer.
看这里  他死于飞机失事
Get this...he dies in a plane crash
正好在那张专辑出版两天前死的
2 days before that CD I was talking about comes out.
但更奇怪的是
But it gets better.
这家伙  贝斯手  叫桑普森
This guy? He's the bass player. His name's Sampson.
这不是艺名
That's not a stage name.
他在接受采访时说
He gives an interview where he says that
自从坠机后  乐队一直无法在一起演奏
the band has not been able to play together since the plane crash,
-因为  -他们被诅咒了
- because...  - They were cursed.
说对了
Yup. Bingo.
也许布兰登说的就是这事
Maybe that's what Brandon was talking about.
但是这不是诅咒
Yeah, except it's not the curse.
而是主唱的鬼魂作祟
It's the lead singer's ghost.
贾里德
Jared.
这里有联系电话吗
Is there contact information in here?
不是  幸运的是
No, but  it's a good thing
我们这区叫桑普森的不多
there aren't too many guys with the first name Sampson in our zip code.
他在给电台做广告配乐
This guy writes commercial jingles for the radio.
你太强了
You rock.
没错  是的
Yes, I do.
我要回去工作了
I gotta get back to work.
好
All right...
这是贾里德死后我们的第一次演奏
the first gig we did after Jared died should be on here somewhere.
那是  那是贾里德吗
Is that...  is that Jared?
是
Yeah.
他们之间有很怪异的心灵感应
They had that telepathy only those weird, creative types have.
他们从小就很铁  所以能有这份默契
Best friends since childhood, too, so that helped.
真是糊涂了
Where's my head?
不是这张碟
This is the wrong DVD.
那是谁
who is that?
杉迪  贾里德的女友
Oh. Sandy, Jared's girlfriend.
你们在做什么
What are you guys doing?
布兰登写了首情歌  我们打算排练一下
Brandon has a love song we're trying to get off the ground.
关于谁的  布兰登
Who's it about, Brandon?
你们准备好后再来找我吧
You know, let me know when you guys are ready to work.
看来布莱登不怎么喜欢她
I guess Brandon didn't like her very much.
不是很喜欢
Not too much.
他们都想得到贾里德的关注
They competed for Jared's attention.
这是丧礼之后一个月
This is a month after the funeral.
贾里德走后  布莱登试着主唱  可是
With Jared gone, Brandon tried vocals. But...
等等  按暂停
Wait, pause it.
那看上去像10吗
Does that look like a "10" to you?
我看不出
I don't see it.
[洛克兰大学]
我直说吧
Let me get this straight.
那个深红什么来着
The crimson  whatever they are,
他们做不了音乐  却来怪罪诅咒
they can't play music, and now they're blaming it on a curse?
鸽子
Doves. Yeah.
总之  他们受到了阻碍
Anyway, something's been getting in their way,
我认为  恰巧在主唱死了之后
and I think since the lead singer's ghost died
他们就再没能演奏
just about the same time as they stopped being able to play,
两者之间必有联系
It might be related.
说到流行乐的诅咒  我很惊奇
You know what fascinates me about pop culture curses?
歌迷对诅咒的妄想能给乐队带来极大影响
The delusional weight that the fans attribute to the curse.
你听过"保罗死了"的恶作剧吗
Have you heard of the "Paul is dead" hoax?
略有耳闻  保罗·麦卡特尼吗[摇滚明星]
A little. Paul, as in Mccartney?
对  简单地说
Yeah. Well, in a nutshell,
一群甲壳虫粉丝把音量开到最大
a bunch of beatlemaniacs turned the volume way up on
听"永远的草莓地"
Strawberry Fields Forever,
然后自以为听到了  "我埋葬了保罗"
and they think they hear "I buried Paul."
突然间谣言四起
Next thing you know, rumors pop up
说可爱的小伙子出车祸死了
that the cute one went toes-up in a car crash.
承认吧  你就是那个散播谣言的粉丝
All right, admit it. You were the beatlemaniac who started that rumor.
亲爱的  要真是我就好了
Oh, sweetheart. If only. Are you kidding me?
如果是我散播的
If I started that rumor?
那将会是最精彩的谣言
That would have been the best.
但不是我
But it wasn't me.
是约翰·列侬录音时搞的鬼[甲壳虫乐队成员]
It was John Lennon's studio trickery.
他唱的是  "小红莓果酱"
He said, "cranberry sauce".
仅此而已
That was it.
而你所说的物理表现
Now, you're talking about a physical manifestation,
他们是感觉到虚弱  发挥不佳吗
where people are actually getting ill, playing poorly?
-没错  -对此  有个完美的解释
- Exactly.  - Well, there's a perfectly reasonable explanation for all of that.
那叫做次声
It's--well, it's called infrasound.
那是什么
What's that?
次声  是一种频率
Well, infrasound...  is a frequency...
有点像
That's not unlike...
别弄了  像是用指甲刮黑板一样
Please don't do that. It sounds like nails on a chalkboard.
用指甲刮黑板
Like nails on a chalkboard.
不同频率的声音  对不同的人有不同的影响
See, different frequencies affect different people in different ways.
但是次声的频率极低
But infrasound is a frequency so low
我们根本听不到
that we can't even hear it at all.
但是人们可以感觉到
But human beings can feel it.
感觉到骨头的震动  让我们不舒服
It rattles our bones, it makes us sick.
迷信的说法是
Now, the wives' tale is that
鬼魂要让人们知道他的存在时
when ghosts want to make their presence felt,
他们就用次声
they use that frequency.
那么
Ok, so...
如果这说法是真的
say that the tale is true,
主唱的鬼魂通过扩音器和扬声器
and that the lead singer's ghost pulled a frequency
发出了那种频率的声音
through the amp and speakers,
的确会让人不舒服  对吗
it could make someone sick, right?
理论上是的
In theory.
那理论上说  怎么才能抵消掉它
Ok, so theoretically, how do we counteract it?
那就必须降低它的声强
Uh, well, you have to tune off of it.
用电子乐器弹最低的G和弦
Go to the lowest "g" chord available on an electrical instrument.
那会使声音的谐振归一化
Uh, that would naturalize the vibrative harmonies
听起来就不那么反胃了
and make the music a little less...stomach-churning.
那数字10又是什么意思呢
And what about the number 10?
那个意义就很广泛了
That's a pretty broad topic.
和这有什么关联  这数字一直出现
Does it have any relevance? It keeps popping up.
如果和你说的诅咒有关  我不清楚
If it has something to do with your curse, I don't know.
我得去查查
I'll look into it.
喂
Hello?
你好  迪莉娅
Hi, Delia.
修钢琴要多少钱
How much to fix the piano?
这样吧  那帮我个忙
Ok, you know what? Do me a favor
问问只买部件要多少钱
and just find out how much it is for just the parts.
我认识个朋友会修  能打折
I think I know somebody who can fix the piano for us at a discount.
你怎么知道我懂钢琴
So how'd you find out I knew about pianos?
我听说你有受过古典乐训练
I heard that you were classically trained,
我就瞎猜你会
and I took a wild guess.
你调查过我了吗
Have you been checking up on me?
一点点
A little.
那天你提到诅咒  我有些好奇
When you mentioned a curse,I got curious.
我认为你的问题不在于此
I don't think that's your problem.
你总是刚见面就问私人问题吗
Do you always ask personal questions of people you just met?
实际上  是的
Actually, yes.
你为什么在夜总会工作
Why do you work in a club?
我需要工作
Because I need a job.
如果你想让我声泪俱下地承认
And before you try to get a tearful confession out of me
我做梦都想回归舞台
about how much I wish I could be up there,
你还是别多此一举了
let me just save you the trouble.
我每天醒来都想回舞台
I wake up every morning wanting that.
但我做不到
But I can't.
我无能为力了
And there's nothing I can do about it.
布兰登  我
Brandon, I--
说到天赋  我略懂一些
I know a little about having a gift
也理解你会为之苦恼
and being frustrated by it.
我能帮助你
I think I can help you.
你都不认识我
You don't even know me.
是的  但我只要求你弹一曲
You're right. But all I'm asking you to do is play one song.
如果钢琴出什么问题  我可不负责
If anything happens to this piano, I'm not responsible.
同意
Agreed.
继续弹
Keep playing.
一会儿我让你按低音G  你就按  好吗
But when I tell you, hit the low "g", ok?
为什么
Why?
相信我
Just trust me.
让他弹那个
Make him play it.
弹什么
Play what?
-什么  -弹"第十"
- What?  - Play the tenth.
我问一句无关的话
I know that this is gonna sound random,
你之前弹过"第十"吗
but have you ever played the tenth?
不知道这是什么吗
You don't know what that is.
不知道
Nope.
你的音乐老师呢
What about music teachers?
他们之中有谁让你弹过"第十"吗
Did any of them ever ask you to play the tenth?
我一生只有一个音乐老师
I had one music teacher my whole life.
非常有才能的一个人
Quite accomplished, actually.
他为纽约爱乐乐团演奏过钢琴
He played piano for the New York Philharmonic.
还给他们写过几首交响曲
Wrote some symphonies for them, too.
但他已经埋在我妈边上了
And he's buried right next to my mom.
他是你父亲
It's your dad.
是的
Yeah.
没听说过什么"第十"
And the tenth never came up.
[洛克兰大学  音乐图书馆]
-给你  -谢谢
- Here you are.  - Thank you.
作曲  帕特里克·罗特
打扰一下
Excuse me.
问个傻问题
Crazy question.
这里有帕特里克·罗特的九首交响曲
You have Patrick Roth's other 9 symphonies here.
你知道有第十首吗
Do you know anything about a tenth?
让我查查
Uh, let me check.
上面说  在完成之前他就去世了
Oh, it says here he passed away before he could complete it.
不过  档案里保存有前三个乐章
Although, we do have his first 3 movements on file.
明白了  我能复印一份吗
I see. Could I get a copy of that score?
当然  我们还有他排练时的录音
Sure. We also have recordings of his symphony rehearsals.
我能听一下吗
Can I hear them?
他一定要弹
He must play it!
这就是你的目的
Is that what you want?
你要布兰登弹这首曲子吗
Brandon to play this?
不
No!
你没明白
You're not getting it!
古典乐
Classical music.
是的  我刚想明白
Yeah. I just found out myself.
虽然线索围绕着"十"
I know that it revolves around the tenth.
可我觉得更像是"弹奏第十交响曲"
Um, but it's more like play the tenth symphony,
可我找到的这首交响曲还没完成
and the one that I found wasn't even finished.
不不  我能搞定这个
No, no.  I can make this work. This I can make work.
我倒是希望能早点得到消息
Sure, I would have loved having this information
我刚答应摇滚名人堂里的某位熟女
before I promised sexual favors to a very unappealing woman
给她提供性服务
at the rock and roll hall of fame,
也许你的问题就是你的答案
but maybe your problem is actually your solution.
九的诅咒吗
The curse of the ninth?
所有伟大的作曲家
All the great composers died after
都在完成第九交响曲后逝世
completing their ninth symphony.
包括贝多芬  马勒  布鲁克纳
you're talking Beethoven, Mahler, Bruckner.
都是第十交响曲写到一半时死的
They all croaked halfway through their tenth.
这诅咒是真的吗
Is this curse real?
不是  跟诅咒完全扯不上
No. No, no. It's not a real curse at all.
他们都死于性病导致的脑中风
These guys all died from having their brains rotted from venereal disease,
说是诅咒是为了让他们听上去更伟大
but saying it's a curse makes it sound more respectable.
鬼魂会不会回来完成自己的作品
And what about a ghost coming back to finish his work?
有这样的记载吗
Is there anything in here about that?
有谣传说巴赫因为受贝多芬的鬼魂纠缠
Well, it's rumored that Brahms was so haunted by Beethoven's ghost
他二十年没写出一个字来
he couldn't write a word for 20 years.
太有建设性了  谢谢
That is brilliant. Thank you.
等等
Wait. Wait.
你冲出去在墙上留下个人形大洞之前
Hey, before you leave a Melinda-shaped hole in that wall,
你说你的征兆里有鸽子
you said there were doves in your symbolism?
深红鸽子  那个乐队的名字
Crimson Doves.That was the name of the band.
听这个
Listen to this.
鸽子之死
"The death of a dove,
从征兆学来说  暗示着厄运
symbolically speaking, indicates misfortune.
如果鸽子死在某人家附近
And the death of a dove near someone's house
意味着那屋里的某人即将死去
means the impending death of someone in that house."
也许这主唱之死
Maybe this lead singer's death,
不只是巧合
isn't just a coincidence.
也许吧
Yeah. Maybe.
我能看见亡者
I can see the dead,
你父亲的鬼魂正缠着你
and your father's ghost is attached to you.
你是不是想说
So is this the part where you say,
我看到名字里有P
"I'm getting a "p" name."
我回答  帕特里克
And I say, "Patrick."
你就说  他要你不用担心钱
And you say,"he wants you to stop worrying about money."
我就回答
And I say--
你父亲比你矮3英寸
your father is 3 inches shorter than you.
他的发际线后移
His hairline is receding.
说话带有欧洲口音  也许是德国口音
He has a soft European accent. German, I think.
他看上去很急躁
Seems like an impatient guy,
最后一次看见他时
and the last time I was with him,
他一直冲我喊  说我没明白
he kept telling me how I wasn't getting it.
够了吗
How am I doing?
他以前经常对我这么说
He used to say that to me all the time.
那时我常练琴
When I would practice.
一天四小时
4 hours a day.
每天如此
Every day
他让我弹奏他的交响曲
He made me play his symphonies.
你没明白  布兰登
You're not getting it, Brandon.
你拍子没跟上
You're off the beat.
你受管弦乐的影响了
Your orchestra is lapping you.
不要看下面
Don't look down.
答案不在你手上
The answer isn't in your hands,
在这里
it's here.
一定要弹对  否则就别弹了
Play it right.  Or don't play at all.
鬼魂的滞留是因为他们有未了的心愿
Ghosts stay behind because they have unfinished business with the living.
我认为你父亲阻止你演奏
I think your father trying to ruin your music...
是因为他要你完成这个
is because he wants you to finish this.
你明白你在要求我做什么吗
Do you have any idea what you're asking me to do here?
这人让我的人生如此痛苦
The man made my life miserable.
你却要我揣摩他的想法
And now you want me to get inside of his head?
我理解你  但如果你能完成交响曲
Look, I understand. But if you complete the symphony,
我就能让他超度
I can cross him over.
那是什么意思
Wh--what does that mean?
意味着  你又能演奏音乐了
It means you can play music again.
你的音乐
Your music.
你看到计算器了吗
Hey, have you seen the calculator?
你想过吗
Have you thought about
明天打算怎么给你爸过生日
what you want to do for your dad's birthday tomorrow?
什么也不做
How about nothing?
内德  看着我
Ned, look at me.
这很重要
This is important.
我真的想做些什么
I really want to do it.
随便什么  都好吧
Whatever. That's fine.
那架电子钢琴卖得很火啊
That electric piano is the hit of the town.
已经三个人出价想买了
I've already had 3 bids on it.
那应该谢谢他修好了琴
Uh, well, you have him to thank for fixing it.
布兰登  这是迪莉娅
Brandon, Delia.
迪莉娅  这是布兰登
Delia, Brandon.
他很有艺术家脾气
He's very artistic.
只要能为店里带来生意
As long as he brings traffic through the store,
随便他怎么耍个性
he can be as artistic as he wants.
跟上
Come on.
你好  内德
Hi, Ned.
我对父亲的作曲风格很了解
I have a pretty good sense of my dad's composing style,
不过我还得从头弹一遍
but I'm gonna have to play it through once
感受一下他想要表达什么
just to get a feel for what he was trying to say.
我能帮上什么忙吗
Is there anything I can help you with?
有  你有没有录音机
Yeah. Uh,  Do you have a tape recorder?
明晚的安排  你还没给我答复
You never answered my question about tomorrow night.
记得你和你爸都喜欢焦糖布丁吗
Do you remember the creme brulee that you and dad always liked?
也许我能做出来
Maybe I could make that.
或许我们什么也不该做
Or maybe we shouldn't do anything.
为什么
How come?
因为已经过了三年了
Because it's been 3 years.
因为
Because it
内德
Ned.
我们得谈谈这事
I want to talk about this.
我有一篇"杀死嘲鸟"的报告
I have a report due on to kill a mockingbird.
落在里屋了
I, um--left it in the back room.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
这个行吗
How's this?
很好
Oh, it's perfect.
你能做得到
You can do this.
上次我漏弹了一个音
Last time I missed a note,
差点被他打到吐血
my dad almost drew blood.
现在他变成了鬼
Now that he's a ghost,
谁知道他会做什么
who knows what he'll do?
有时  鬼魂有话要传递给生者
Sometimes, ghosts have messages for the living.
我需要你的帮助才能理解
I might need your help to understand it.
一个字  一句话
A word, a phrase.
只有你们才能理解的话
Something that might have meaning for the two of you.
布兰登  你父亲来了
Brandon, your dad's here.
我没有弹低音G
I didn't hit the low "g".
没关系
No, it's ok.
没关系  他也许只想看着你弹
It's ok. He probably just needed to see you play.
怎么回事
What is that?
现在应该没事了
I think we're ok.
帮我
Help me.
按低音G
Hit the low "g".
贾里德
Jared.
等等
Wait, wait, wait.
你是不是想说
Are you trying to tell me that...
我父亲已经走了
my dad is gone,
还有另一个鬼魂在这吗
and there's another ghost?
是  缠着他的是贾里德
Yeah, attached to him. Uh, it's Jared.
他现在在店里
He's in the store.
兄弟  最近如何
How's it going, buddy?
他在跟你打招呼
He says hi.
那真是
That's
天  那真是太好了
my god, that's awesome.
你为什么会来这
Yeah. Why are you here?
来保护布兰登
To protect Brandon.
他在保护你
He's protecting you.
-保护他什么  -以免他浪费时间
- From who?  - From that waste of time.
浪费时间  你在说什么
Waste of time? What are you talking about?
我知道
I know.
那时  我们一起玩音乐一年了
We'd been playing together for about a year.
你们觉得如何
What did you guys think?
-我觉得不行  -很好听
- I really don't think it works.  - It was beautiful.
你有填词吗
Do you have lyrics?
我还在写
I'm still working on them.
你们想要吃的或喝的吗
And you guys want something to eat, or drink, or--?
父亲
Dad.
你们两个  出去
You two, leave.
马上
Right now.
你就为了这个  放弃了多年的训练
So this is what you decide to throw your training away for?
这比莫扎特还好吗
This is better than Mozart?
莫扎特在他的时代酷毙了
Mozart rocked out in his day.
这是你告诉我的
You taught me that.
你要浪费你的时间
You want to waste your time,
我不能阻止你
I can't stop you.
但是我不能原谅你浪费我的时间
But what I can't forgive you for is wasting mine.
从那之后
After that,
我跟我父亲开始冷战  任何事
my dad and I stopped. Everything.
不说话  不住在一起
Talking, being in the same room.
贾里德成为了我的家人
Jared became my family.
我想他现在还是
I guess he still is.
布兰登的父亲出现  你做了什么
So, Brandon's dad shows up and you what?
打跑他  然后毁掉我的店吗
Beat him up, and then decide to wreck my store?
我在死后不能弹琴已经很惨
It was bad enough that I died and couldn't play anymore.
可后来  我跟随布兰登看他的演奏
But then I followed Brandon to his next gig
看到那混蛋在扰乱音律
and saw that douche mucking around with the sound.
让布兰登弹得乱七八糟
Disrupted, made Brandon play like crap.
他在说什么
Wh--what--what's he saying?
他说是你父亲在影响你演奏
He says your dad was affecting your playing,
我们感到的震动
and the rumble we felt?
就是他赶走你父亲的方式
That was his way of fighting him off.
意图是好的
Good intentions aside,
但这没有解决问题
this is not solving the problem.
你父亲希望你完成交响乐
Your dad wants you to finish the symphony,
在那之前他是不会超度的
and he's not gonna cross over until he does that.
也许还有第三选项
Well, maybe there's a third option.
也许伟大的父亲需要认可自己的儿子
Maybe mr. Father of the year needs to accept who his son is.
只要他离开布兰登
Once he leaves Brandon alone,
我就离开他
I'll leave him alone.
喂
Hello.
梅  是我
Hey, Mel. It's me.
一切还好吗
Is everything ok?
实际上  我有点害怕
No, actually. I'm a little freaked out.
内德从上车开始
You know, Ned was very jumpy
就一直很兴奋
the whole car ride home and all through dinner.
他说他有件事情必须要做
And then he told me that he had to go do something and...
我找不到他
I can't find him.
你要我和吉姆帮你找他吗
Would you want jim and I to help you look for him?
我觉得应该放他一小时  再...
I feel like I should give it an hour or so before...
我真的不知所措了
I really lose my mind. Ok?
如果你看到
So but if you see him
看到他去了店里或广场上
if you see him at the store or in the square,
给我个电话  好吗
will you call me, please?
带他回家好吗
Will you bring him home?
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
内德的短信  "你能看见鬼魂"
内德
Ned.
我说错了吗
Am I wrong?
我要你仔细听着
I want you to listen to me very closely.
我们不能告诉你妈妈
We cannot tell your mom.
-为什么  -原因很复杂
- Why not?  - It's complicated.
你能帮助那个玩吉他的人
So, you can help this guitarist guy,
却不帮我
but you can't help me?
帮你什么  内德
With what, Ned?
我可以帮助你什么
What can I possibly help you with?
我要你找到我父亲
I need you to find my dad.
在他死后
After he died
那时我还很小
when I was young...er--
我认为我看到他了
I thought I saw him.
我妈说那是我想象出来
My mom just told me I imagined it.
但我没有  是吗
But I wasn't, was I?
不  你没有
No. No, you weren't.
那你还能看见我父亲
So, you can still see my dad?
不  不是这样子的
No. It doesn't really work that way.
为什么不行
Why not?
因为我不能控制哪个鬼会来见我
Because I have no control over which ghosts appear to me.
你帮助过那人的父亲
You helped that other guy's dad!
我听到你说鬼魂给你提示和信息
And I heard you saying that ghosts give you signs and messages.
那正是我妈妈所需要的
That's just what my mom needs.
一条信息而已
A message.
我妈一直都很伤心
Cause my mom is hurting.
内德  你去哪里
Ned, where you going?
回家
Home.
别担心  我没事的
Don't worry. I'll be fine.
感谢你的帮助
Thanks for your help.
要吃点什么
Want anything to eat?
你看不见查理  对吧
You don't see Charlie anywhere, do you?
看不见
No.
最糟的是
And the worst part is that
我希望能告诉迪莉娅和内德他没离开
I wish I could tell delia and Ned that he's here.
但他不在这
But he's not.
我有没有说过  我很庆幸
Have I ever told you how happy I am I'm--
我不是你
I'm not you.
这算什么安慰
Well, that's not helping.
不是因为你所做的事情
It's not the way of what you do,
而是那份责任
it's the responsibility.
以及你的处世方法
I mean, how you have to do it.
比如  一方面
For example, on one hand
你需要说服布兰登不再隐藏他的天赋
you have to convince Brandon not hide his gift.
但另一方面
But then on the other hand...
却对内德和迪莉娅隐藏了自己的天赋
you've been doing exactly that yourself with Ned and Delia.
你认为我应该告诉她
So, you think I should tell her.
不  不是
No. No.
你应该在时机成熟时向迪莉娅坦白
You should come clean with Delia when you feel its right.
而不要等到被内德逼到墙角
And not because Ned's got you boxed into a corner.
不过
But...
我觉得你应该让我跟内德谈谈
what I do think is that you should let me talk to Ned.
你手上的事太多了
You got too much on your plate already.
谢谢你
Thank you.
这是丈夫的职责
It's what I'm here for.
你没有理解琴弦的部分
You're not getting the string section.
你弹得太甜美
You're too sweet.
音符很甜美
The notes are sweet.
你不需要弹得这么甜美
You don't have to play it so sweetly.
你没有理解  没有明白
You are not getting it. You are not getting it.
-帕特里克  -你要帮助布兰登完成第十曲
- Patrick.  - You have to help Brandon with the tenth.
我已经尽力了
I've done everything that I can.
你还在这里的原因是  自私
The reason that you're still here is because of your selfishness.
布兰登不会完成你的交响乐
Brandon is not going to complete your symphony.
不是我的第十交响乐
It's not my tenth.
是我儿子的
My son's.
你们有没有在这碟里录过第十首歌
Did you guys ever record a tenth track for the CD?
那只是他胡乱弹奏的
It was just something he was messing with.
他和贾里德决定曲目排序时
When he and Jared were figuring out the track order,
并没有收录那首歌
it didn't make the cut.
我不知道最后怎么了
I don't know what happened to it.
但杉迪知道
But Sandy would.
她一直都跟贾里德在一起
She was with Jared the whole time.
车祸后  她经历了太多
She went through enough after the crash.
我不希望把她扯进来
I don't want to drag her back into this.
如果不重要  我是不会提出来的
I wouldn't bring it up unless it was really important.
如果布兰登能弹奏这首歌
If Brandon can get through this song,
也许能帮助他重新弹琴
maybe it'll help him play again.
杉迪  我是梅林达
Sandy, hi, I'm Melinda.
有什么需要我帮忙的
Hi. Can I help you?
实际上  我希望能和你谈谈深红鸽子
Actually I was hoping that we could talk about the Crimson Doves.
我很久没联系他们了
Man, I haven't thought about those guys in a while.
你没有跟布兰登联系吗
So, you didn't keep in touch with Brandon?
没有
No.
我希望能从你那儿了解一下第十首歌
I was hoping you would shed some light on song number 10.
专辑里只有九首歌
There were only nine cutson the album.
是没错  但你记得那首
Yeah. But you'll remember the song.
贾里德不喜欢其中和弦的那首
It was the one with the chords that Jared wasn't crazy about.
你怎么不去找布兰登
Why don't you go talk to Brandon?
因为这中间太复杂
Well, because it's complicated.
我认为贾里德有影响到布兰登
I think that Jared got in Brandon's way.
如果我问布兰登
And if i talk to Brandon,
我满耳都是他挚友有多么铁
all I'm gonna get is an earful about how great his best friend was.
所以你就找他女朋友来打听事实
So, you go to the girlfriend for the real story.
你怎么会认为我比较诚实
What makes you think I'm gonna be anymore honest.
因为你曾在那
Because you were there.
那首歌引发他俩争执是有原因的  对吗
There's a reason that that song came between them, isn't there?
是因为你  对吗
It was about you, wasn't it?
贾里德知道吗
Did Jared know?
他发现铁哥们喜欢自己的女友后
He must have been furious to find out
反应一定很强烈
that his best friend had feelings for his girl.
的确  但并不是因为那首歌是写我的
He was. But not because the song was about me.
那他为什么生气
Then what was he upset about?
因为那歌写得很棒
At how good the song was.
谁都知道布兰登有惊人的天赋
See, everybody knew that Brandon was scary talented.
这也是贾里德把他招进乐团的始因
That's why Jared wanted him in the band to begin with.
也只有布兰登自己不知道
And the only person who couldn't see it was Brandon.
但在他写了那首歌后
But after he wrote that song--
他开始威胁到贾里德
he started outgrowing Jared.
他们为是否收录那首歌而大吵了一架
They had a fight about whether or not the song was going on the CD.
唱片公司想要放
The record company wanted it.
布兰登也希望放  但
Brandon wanted it. But...
贾里德不希望
Jared didn't.
他乘飞机从录音室回来
He got on that plane to come back to the studio
打算亲手删除那首歌
and remove it personally.
但他没有成功
Only he never made it.
葬礼后
After the funeral,
布兰登找齐每一卷录有那首歌的带子
Brandon gathered every recording he'd made of the song.
快停下
Stop it.
别管我
Just leave me alone.
走开
Get out of here!
滚
GO!
他烧毁了所有的带子
He burnt everything?
他这么做是为了尊重贾里德的愿望
He thought he was honoring Jared's wishes.
我本以为你能够帮我
I really thought you were going to
让他重新开始弹琴
be able to help me get him to play again.
稍等一会
Wait.
这是他第一次录的样带
This is the first demo he ever made of it.
跟歌词一起
The one with lyrics.
他拿来问我的意见
He wanted to know what I thought about it.
告诉他  我很珍爱它
Tell him I cherished it.
迪莉娅  真好
Hey, Delia. Excellent.
我在找内德
Hey, I was actually looking for Ned.
我想也许
And I was wondering if...
你哭了  怎么了
you're crying.What's wrong?
没事
Nothing.
梅林达告诉了我
Mel told me, um...
今天是查理的生日  对吗
today would be Charlie's birthday, right?
是
Yeah.
还有
That...
我很想念跟儿子一起玩乐的时光
and I really miss hanging out with my son.
我很抱歉  吉姆  又开始唠叨了
I'm sorry, jim. You didn't ask for this.
如果你想谈谈的话
If you ever want to talk about it...
我愿意听
this is cool.
这是查理
That's Charlie.
你们看起来很开心
You look very happy.
曾经是
We were.
12年了
For 12 long years.
准备好了  只有13秒
We're ready.We got 13 seconds.
笑一个
Smile.
然后有一天  他在取款机边站着
And then one day he stopped at an atm.
被人抢劫了  还...
He got robbed and...
天  我讨厌在说重点时流泪
god, I hate crying when I'm trying to make a point.
没关系
That's all right.
他们在前一天晚上发生过争执
They got into a big argument the night before.
内德想预支零花钱买一款游戏
Ned just wanted to get his allowance early so he could buy this game.
查理不同意
Charlie told him he'd have to wait.
内德就叫他"混珠"
So, Ned called him an asshat.
有这个词吗
Is that even a word?
我也不清楚
I don't really know.
出于原则  我们把他禁足了
So, we grounded him more on principle than anything else.
但查理第二天就让他解禁了  可是
And Charlie was gonna let him off the hook the next day, but...
他再也没回来
He never came home.
所以我每年都要庆祝他的生日
That's why I want to celebrat his birthday every year--
这样
so that...
内德才能记住和他父亲的美好时光
Ned can remember all the good things about his dad.
孩子  你和我谈谈吧
Hey, kid  you and me. Let's talk.
干嘛这个反应
What makes you say that?
你无缘无故地来找我
You coming to me, out of the blue?
我知道接下来会怎样  你会威胁我不要乱说
I know what comes next, you threaten me to stay quiet.
还好我把钳子放在后车厢了
Well, it's a good thing I left the pliers back in the van.
听着  我妻子告诉了我
Listen, my wife tells me sometimes
在你爸死后  你经常看到他
you used to see your dad after he died.
坐下
Sit down.
我父亲死后  我的状态很差
I was on pretty bad terms when my dad died.
之后我强迫自己压抑着
And after I just kicked myself for not saying...
不说出心里的想法
all the things I wanted to.
但梅林达对我说了句很有帮助的话
But then Melinda told me something that really helped.
她哪儿都看不到我父亲
She didn't see my dad anywhere.
那是好事
That's a good thing?
那是天大的好事
That's a great thing.
那代表着他已经超度了
'Cause it meant that he crossed over, you know.
进入了那道光
Into the light.
那是什么  天堂
What is that, heaven?
我认为那是死后的极乐世界
I think it's a place the dead go to be at peace.
只有看到亲人都过得很好时  他们才会去那
And they only go there when the people they've left behind are ok.
我父亲已经不在这里了  对吗
My dad isn't here anymore, is he?
-你有手机吗  -有
- You got a phone?  - Yeah.
这是我手机号
This is my cell.
你要想找我谈谈男人之间的事
You want to talk to me about guy stuff,
只要给我一个电话
I'm a phone call away.
就这么办
This is how it works.
不向任何人透露梅林达的能力  好吗
We don't tell anybody about what Melinda can do, ok?
我能替你保守任何秘密
I'll keep any secret you want.
你替我保守这个
You keep this one.
可以吗
deal?
好了  我得去上班了
All right. I gotta go to work.
克兰西
Clancy.
我能去吗
Can I come?
贾里德这样对你多久了
How long has Jared been doing this to you?
我不知道
I don't know.
医生告诉我  我命不久矣时
When the doctor said I was dying,
我试着寻找布兰登
I tried to reach out to Brandon.
去告诉他我很抱歉
Tell him I was sorry.
我当时很害怕
I--I was so scared.
我曾如此待他
After the way I treated him.
这就是你留下的原因吗
Is that why you stayed behind?
为了道歉
To apologize?
不是
No.
我的生命中还有未了之事
Something in my life was unfinished.
我以为是因为我的第十交响乐
I thought it was my symphony.
后来  我看见我儿子表演
And then I saw my son perform.
他弹得很棒
He was beautiful.
我简直无法相信
I couldn't believe it.
不敢相信  我居然从没让自己
Couldn't believe that I had never let myself...
了解他
see him.
而他却一直在阻扰
He kept on getting in the way.
-贾里德  -对
- Jared.  - Yes.
一开始就是他在破坏布兰登的演奏
From the beginning it was him destroying Brandon's playing.
每次我试着阻止他
But every time I try to stop him,
他令我虚弱无力
He drains me.
我认为贾里德在利用你
I think Jared is using you.
你对布兰登的愧疚
The sadness over what you lost with Brandon,
只会促使他更强大
it's only making him stronger.
你必须抵抗他
You have to fight him.
我不行
I can't.
我一无所有了
I've got nothing left.
这些年我一直在找这张样碟
You know I've been searching for this demo for years?
看看  你帮我找到了
And look at that--you lead me right to it.
不  等等
No. Wait!
你不想让布兰登弹这首曲子  我明白
You don't want Brandon to play the song. I get it.
但你不必这样  贾里德
There's a better way,Jared.
你想说那能带来宁静  爱与理解的白光
Oh, you mean your little peace, love and understanding white light?
对  我见过
Yeah. I've seen it.
你没弄懂  我现在的能力
What you don't get is that I can do
是任何摇滚明星梦寐以求的
what every rock star dreams of now.
我能让人颤抖
I can make people tremble.
我能让土地移动
I can make the earth move.
为什么要阻挠布兰登
Why get in Brandon's way?
是我让布兰登认识自我的
I made Brandon who he is.
我也能收回来
And I can take it away.
你有什么
What do you have on your side?
小狗和彩虹吗
Puppy dogs and rainbows?
布兰登的父亲对我毫无威胁
Brandon's dad means nothing to me.
你也是
And neither do you.
我不会超度的
I'm not crossing over.
绝不
Ever!
我不明白为什么你要我这么做
I don't understand why you're asking me to do this.
我父亲不会让我弹我的音乐
My dad is not going to let me play my music.
看到了吗
You see?
一直阻扰你的不是你父亲
Your father isn't the one that's been getting in your way.
而是贾里德
It's Jared.
他不会这么做的
He wouldn't do that.
他会
Yes, he would.
他曾嫉妒你为杉迪写的那首歌
He was jealous about the song you wrote for Sandy.
我毁掉了那首歌
I destroyed that song.
那还不够
That wasn't good enough.
你的天赋威胁到他
He was threatened by how good you are.
而你父亲则不同
And the person who wasn't was your father.
告诉他  第一首歌是受到了
Tell him the first song was inspired,
格伦·古尔德的启发
Glenn Gould-esque.
他说你唱片第一首歌是格伦·古尔德风格的
He said the first song on your cd was like Glenn Gould.
他  有听过我的音乐吗
He...listened to my music?
是的
Yes.
他活着时为什么不告诉我
Why couldn't he tell me that when he was alive?
因为他恨你
Because he hated you.
布兰登  你父亲想要帮助你
Brandon, your father wants to help you.
他希望你演唱给杉迪的那首歌
He wants you to sing Sandy's song
以及所有你曾写过的歌
and everything else you've ever written.
这也许会有帮助
Maybe this will help.
发生了什么
What happened?!
是贾里德  他在伤害你父亲
It's Jared.He's hurting your father.
你别想总是得逞
You can't just keep doing this.
要赌一下吗
Want to bet?
就这样吗
Is that it?
你可以弄断所有的琴弦
You can break all the strings you want, man.
但再没有人能阻止我弹琴
No one is going to stop me from playing anymore.
Running Away - Midnight Hour
* Don't lie and say that it's ok *
* it's all right if there's nothing more to say *
那是什么
What does that mean?
那道光
That light?
那说明着你准备好超度了
It means you're ready to cross over.
他会没事的
He's gonna be all right.
是的
Yes.
* And faster than you can follow me *
* from this lonely place *
我真希望我不必离开
I just wish I didn't have to go.
不是现在
Not now.
能再待会儿
Not just yet.
* Yeah  I am leaving today *
是时候了
It's time.
* I'll never let you find me *
* I'm leaving you behind with the past *
谢谢你
Thank you.
* No, I won't look back *
* And I wanna hear your reasons wanna hear you tell me *
* why I should stay try *
* try to understand me *
* try to understand what I say*
* when I say can't stay *
* I'm... I'm moving off of this place leaving and I won't quit *
* I'm running away *
* I'm leaving this place *
你觉得这次重聚巡演怎样
So, how do you think the reunion tour went?
如果有纪念衫  我一定要买
Ohh, if there was a t-shirt,I would have bought it.
等我一会儿
Uh, give me a second.
我得和某人谈谈
I have to talk to somebody.
你没事吗
You'll be ok?
没事的  相信我
Yeah. Trust me.
他无法再伤害任何人了
He can't hurt anybody anymore.
-我就在那里  -好的
- I'll be over there.  - Ok.
不过就是能唱几首歌
Just because you can sing a few songs,
那并不代表什么
doesn't mean anything.
并不代表你会成功
Doesn't mean you'll make it.
也许他不需要成功
Maybe he doesn't need to make it.
他只是需要弹琴
Maybe he just needs to play.
我知道你现在很生气
Look, I know how angry you are right now.
但如果你愿意的话  我可以帮你超度
But if you'll let me, I can help you cross over.
你认为你是镇里唯一有这能力的吗
Think you're the only afterlife game in town?
还有其他的人
There are others around here--
特别希望见到我的人
people who are dying to meet me.
那些灵魂  他们会答应你所有要求
Those other spirits, they will promise you anything.
但他们都在说谎
They're all lying.
会比曾经的 "摇滚大骗局"更糟吗
No worse than the usual rock and roll swindle.
再会
Be seeing you.